<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teach Me To Code</title>
    <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Teach Me To Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.christopherfujino.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Relaunching my Website</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2023-11-25-relaunching-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2023-11-25-relaunching-my-website/</guid>
      <description>So, I have been a bad blogger.
It has been over 7 years since my last post. At that time, coding was a hobby I was interested in growing into my full-time profession. I used my blog as a journal of what I learned. I called it Teach Me to Code because I saw it as a journal of a learner and I imagined more experienced coders might interact and offer me insights.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Agency: Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/drafts/2023-10-13-power-of-agency-ch-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 22:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/drafts/2023-10-13-power-of-agency-ch-1/</guid>
      <description>Foo bar</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching C to a JavaScript Developer, Redux</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/drafts/2021-05-30-teaching-c-to-a-js-dev-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/drafts/2021-05-30-teaching-c-to-a-js-dev-redux/</guid>
      <description>Primitive Types The primitive types in JavaScript are number, string, boolean, undefined, and null.
var num = 42; var str = &amp;#34;Hello, world!&amp;#34;; var bool = true; var undef; // an uninitialized variable has the value `undefined` var nul = null; These types map closely to how a developer would use them in a program: numbers are obviously for counting and arithmetic, strings for storing textual data, booleans for values that must be either true or false, undefined for variables that have not yet been initialized, and null for variables that explicitly do not contain a value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sf.js</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-10-13-sfjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 18:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-10-13-sfjs/</guid>
      <description>I recently went to the Bay Area to visit my brother and got a chance to go to some meetups and mingle with the local nerdfolk. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the meetups I attended and what I learned:
Electron Meetup The first meetup was for the exciting new Node.js-based framework Electron. It lets you build desktop apps in HTML/CSS/JS and then distribute it to Windows/OS X/Linux. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with it, so I was excited to hear more about it, especially since two of the presenters were from Github and part of the Electron team.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A CSS Word-break Bug</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-09-12-word-break-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 16:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-09-12-word-break-bug/</guid>
      <description>So on my last post, I encountered a strange bug on Chrome (but not on Firefox) where some of my text was breaking mid-word, without so much as a hyphen inserted. Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot:
I&amp;rsquo;m using the Hexo framework for my blog, along with a theme from github called Apollo, so I started reading through the SASS files, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t isolate what exactly was causing this strange bug I&amp;rsquo;d never encountered before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching C To A JavaScript Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-07-21-teaching-c-to-a-js-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 17:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-07-21-teaching-c-to-a-js-developer/</guid>
      <description>According to Douglas Crockford, JavaScript is the world&amp;rsquo;s most misunderstood programming language, and I am inclined to agree. Especially in the &amp;rsquo;90s, I think a lot of programmers first encountered JavaScript from a C/C++ or Java background (indeed, JavaScript-inventor Brendan Eich has said that he was tasked with creating Java&amp;rsquo;s little brother to run in the browser). I was one of them. We found the syntax very familiar. In fact, after reading a tutorial or two, I was able to write a slot machine game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ES6 Maps, Weak Maps, and the Determinism of the JavaScript Garbage Collector</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-07-09-hash-maps-es6-maps-and-weak-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 18:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-07-09-hash-maps-es6-maps-and-weak-maps/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have an app with a number of objects, and you&amp;rsquo;d like to store metadata about certain objects. How would you do this? What I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing is creating a special object for the purpose, like so:
var x = { uniqueIdentifier : &amp;#34;this is my first object&amp;#34; }; var y = { uniqueIdentifier : &amp;#34;this is my second object&amp;#34; }; var registry = {}; registry[x.uniqueIdentifier] = &amp;#39;this object is okay&amp;#39;; registry[y.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Git, Dotfiles, and the Dream of a Truly Cross-Platform Work Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-06-28-git-dotfiles-and-the-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 17:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-06-28-git-dotfiles-and-the-dream/</guid>
      <description>So last October I started using Git to track my dotfiles and config files. Although it makes sense to use version control in case you make a change that breaks your system, to me the biggest appeal of doing this was so that I could easily synchronize all my config files between devices. My first commit included config files for npm and vim, and now it&amp;rsquo;s grown to include bash, window managers, and terminal emulators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-06-15-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 16:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/posts/2016-06-15-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Most programming blogs feature posts from veteran programmers teaching others new concepts and techniques. However, I am a beginning programmer and I plan to blog about the things I&amp;rsquo;m learning and the difficulties I&amp;rsquo;m having. Hopefully I can help other beginning programmers, but more importantly I hope people will get involved and teach me to code!
Why I Chose To Use Hexo Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with many different ways to manage a blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/recommendations/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/about/</guid>
      <description>This is my blog about my personal journey in learning programming &amp;amp; web development. It is an outlet for me to process and communicate what I’m learning, and also an opportunity to interact with other coders.
I am excited about clean code, open source software, and learning/teaching. I love refactoring code, run applications in Docker, and streamline my vim config.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Résumé</title>
      <link>https://www.christopherfujino.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.christopherfujino.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>This content does not get interpolated into the template.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
